

PAUL COWAN

• DETAILS •

Glasgow
United Kingdom
7908771391
paul.cowan@cutting.scot

SKILLS

HTML

JavaScript

typescript

react

nodejs

d3/d3js

HTML, CSS

redux

SASS/SCSS

Angular

rxjs

SQL Server, MYSQL, POSTGRES

C#

ASP.NET MVC

RUBY

HOBBIES

Combat sports, boxing, MMA

LINKS

linkedin

PROFILE

My passion is and always has been frontend development. I love the instant visual feedback that is unique to frontend development.

I am an open-source fanatic with <u>over 140+ merged pull requests</u> in the past 12 months alone into many, many, many open source repositories.

I write professionally for logrocket and my own personal blog.

I have over 20 years of experience working on some exceptional frontend pieces of work for companies such as <u>waitrose</u>, <u>the Volvo ocean race</u>, the Scottish and Northern Irish governments and many others.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Developer Experience Consultant at frontside, remote

February 2021 — January 2022

- Helping software teams for companies such as resideo and hp level up their javascript/typescript skills
- React
- Typescript
- Nodejs
- Graphql
- · Spotify Backstage

Frontend Developer Contract at Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

August 2019 — December 2020

- Lead frontend developer on Scottish Governments pvg online https://csg.apply.disclosure.scot/
- helped set up the infrastructure for javascript/typescript development
- react
- typescript
- nodejs
- · terraform
- AWS

Frontend Developer Contract at Screenmedia, Glasgow

June 2019 — August 2019

- Frontend developer for clients of Screenmedia
- React
- typescript
- D3
- Node

Data Visualisations at Continuity2, Glasgow

April 2019 — June 2019

- Bringing data to life in the form of svg data visualisations
- react
- typescript

Contract Software Developer at Waracle, Glasgow, United Kingdom

January 2019 — April 2019

- Full-stack development for an online web portal with azure serverless technologies including blob storage and azure functions.
- Angular
- rxjs
- HTML 5, CSS, sass, Typescript
- Azure (Blob storage, functions)
- Terraform

Frontend Developer Contract at BJSS - Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

June 2017 — December 2018

- Rewrite of the Scottish government disclosure Scotland online application forms for criminal record checks
- https://basic.apply.disclosure.scot/
- react
- typescript
- nodejs

Full Stack Contract Developer at WIPRO - Lloyds Bank, Edinburgh

November 2016 — June 2017

- Working on the Scottish Widows pension portal.
- react
- mobx
- webpack

Full Stack Contract Developer at City Holdings

March 2016 — November 2016

- Working on the Scottish Widows pension portal.
- react
- mobx
- webpack

Full StackContract Developer at Continuity2, Glasgow

September 2007 — November 2012

- Working for a digital agency working on some reasonably sized websites such as waitrose and the Volvo ocean race.
- JQuery
- C#•

Full Stack Contract Developer at Twentysixlondon, London

March 2004 — August 2007

Working for a digital agency working on some reasonably sized websites such as waitrose and the volvo ocean race.

- C#
- ASP.NET

EDUCATION

Scottish Higher Maths – B , Further Education Anniesland, Glasgow

October 2015 — June 2016

COURSES COURSES

O

1 ■ REFERENCES

Richard McGlave from Continuity2 richard.mcglave@continuity2.com